

//  Question_Bank whiuc contaion 50 object / in form of question 
const Question_Bank = [
    {
        question: "Who is known as the 'God of Cricket'?",
        options: ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Virat Kohli", "MS Dhoni", "Ricky Ponting"],
        answer: "Sachin Tendulkar"
    },
    {
        question: "Which country won the first-ever Cricket World Cup in 1975?",options: ["Australia", "England", "West Indies", "India"],answer: "West Indies"
    },
    {
        question: "Who has scored the most international centuries in cricket?",options: ["Virat Kohli", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Ricky Ponting", "Jacques Kallis"],answer: "Sachin Tendulkar"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the highest individual score in ODI cricket?",options: ["264", "237", "219", "200"],answer: "264"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first bowler to take 600 Test wickets?",options: ["Shane Warne", "Muttiah Muralitharan", "Anil Kumble", "James Anderson"],answer: "Muttiah Muralitharan"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Indian cricketer is known as 'Captain Cool'?",options: ["Virat Kohli", "Rohit Sharma", "MS Dhoni", "Kapil Dev"],answer: "MS Dhoni"
    },
    {
        question: "In which year did India win its first Cricket World Cup?",options: ["1983", "1996", "2003", "2011"],answer: "1983"
    },
    {
        question: "Who has taken the most wickets in Test cricket?",options: ["Muttiah Muralitharan", "Shane Warne", "Anil Kumble", "James Anderson"],answer: "Muttiah Muralitharan"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first batsman to score a double century in ODIs?",options: ["Virender Sehwag", "Rohit Sharma", "Chris Gayle", "Sachin Tendulkar"],answer: "Sachin Tendulkar"
    },
    {
        question: "Which country has won the most ICC Cricket World Cups?",options: ["India", "Australia", "West Indies", "England"],answer: "Australia"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the nickname of the Australian cricket team?",options: ["Kangaroos", "Wallabies", "Baggy Greens", "Aussies"],answer: "Baggy Greens"
    },
    {
        question: "Who holds the record for the fastest century in ODIs?",options: ["AB de Villiers", "Chris Gayle", "Virat Kohli", "Shahid Afridi"],answer: "AB de Villiers"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the name of the trophy awarded in the India vs Australia Test series?",options: ["Border-Gavaskar Trophy", "Ashes", "Pataudi Trophy", "Champions Trophy"],answer: "Border-Gavaskar Trophy"
    },
    {
        question: "Who hit six sixes in an over in international cricket first?",options: ["Yuvraj Singh", "Herschelle Gibbs", "Ravi Shastri", "Chris Gayle"],answer: "Herschelle Gibbs"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the length of a cricket pitch in yards?",options: ["20", "22", "24", "18"],answer: "22"
    },
    {
        question: "Who has the record for the highest individual score in Test cricket?",options: ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Brian Lara", "Virender Sehwag", "Steve Smith"],answer: "Brian Lara"
    },
    {
        question: "Which bowler has the record for the best bowling figures in an ODI match?",options: ["Muttiah Muralitharan", "Glenn McGrath", "Stuart Binny", "Chaminda Vaas"],answer: "Chaminda Vaas"
    },
    {
        question: "Who captained India in the 2011 Cricket World Cup final?",options: ["Virat Kohli", "Sourav Ganguly", "MS Dhoni", "Gautam Gambhir"],answer: "MS Dhoni"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the official color of the ICC World Test Championship mace?",options: ["Gold", "Silver", "Platinum", "Bronze"],answer: "Silver"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Indian bowler took a hat-trick in a World Cup match?",options: ["Anil Kumble", "Harbhajan Singh", "Jasprit Bumrah", "Chetan Sharma"],answer: "Chetan Sharma"
    },
    {
        question: "Which team won the 2023 Cricket World Cup?",options: ["India", "England", "Australia", "New Zealand"],answer: "Australia"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the name of the biggest T20 league in the world?",options: ["BBL", "IPL", "CPL", "PSL"],answer: "IPL"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first captain to win the ICC Champions Trophy?",options: ["MS Dhoni", "Ricky Ponting", "Sourav Ganguly", "Graeme Smith"],answer: "Ricky Ponting"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first cricketer to score 10,000 runs in Test cricket?",options: ["Sunil Gavaskar", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Allan Border", "Steve Waugh"],answer: "Sunil Gavaskar"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the diameter of a standard cricket ball?",options: ["5.5 inches", "6 inches", "2.86 inches", "3.5 inches"],answer: "2.86 inches"
    },
    {
        question: "Which country hosted the first-ever Day-Night Test match?",options: ["India", "Australia", "England", "New Zealand"],answer: "Australia"
    },
    {
        question: "Which team has won the most IPL titles?",options: ["Chennai Super Kings", "Mumbai Indians", "Kolkata Knight Riders", "Delhi Capitals"],answer: "Mumbai Indians"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is the fastest bowler to reach 500 Test wickets?",options: ["Muttiah Muralitharan", "Shane Warne", "Glenn McGrath", "Dale Steyn"],answer: "Muttiah Muralitharan"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Indian player was known as 'The Wall'?",options: ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Rahul Dravid", "VVS Laxman", "Sourav Ganguly"],answer: "Rahul Dravid"
    },
    {
        question: "How many balls are there in an over?",options: ["4", "5", "6", "8"],answer: "6"
    },
    {
        question: "Which cricketer has the most double centuries in Test cricket?",options: ["Virat Kohli", "Brian Lara", "Don Bradman", "Sachin Tendulkar"],answer: "Don Bradman"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first batsman to score 10,000 runs in ODI cricket?",options: ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Kumar Sangakkara", "Ricky Ponting", "Sunil Gavaskar"],answer: "Sachin Tendulkar"
    },
    {
        question: "Which bowler has taken the most wickets in a single IPL season?",options: ["Lasith Malinga", "Harshal Patel", "Dwayne Bravo", "Kagiso Rabada"],answer: "Harshal Patel"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the maximum number of overs a bowler can bowl in a T20 match?",options: ["2", "3", "4", "5"],answer: "4"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first Indian to win the ICC Player of the Year award?",options: ["MS Dhoni", "Virat Kohli", "Rahul Dravid", "Sachin Tendulkar"],answer: "Rahul Dravid"
    },
    {
        question: "In which year did the first-ever Test match take place?",options: ["1877", "1888", "1900", "1921"],answer: "1877"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Indian cricketer is nicknamed 'The Hitman'?",options: ["Virat Kohli", "Shikhar Dhawan", "Rohit Sharma", "Suryakumar Yadav"],answer: "Rohit Sharma"
    },
    {
        question: "How many players are there in a cricket team?",options: ["9", "10", "11", "12"],answer: "11"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the distance between the stumps in cricket?",options: ["20 yards", "22 yards", "24 yards", "18 yards"],answer: "22 yards"
    },
    {
        question: "Who won the Orange Cap in IPL 2022?",options: ["Jos Buttler", "David Warner", "KL Rahul", "Faf du Plessis"],answer: "Jos Buttler"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first cricketer to take 10 wickets in a Test innings?",options: ["Anil Kumble", "Jim Laker", "Muttiah Muralitharan", "Shane Warne"],answer: "Jim Laker"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first player to hit 6 sixes in an over in T20 internationals?",options: ["Chris Gayle", "Kieron Pollard", "Yuvraj Singh", "Rohit Sharma"],answer: "Yuvraj Singh"
    },
    {
        question: "Which country has won the most T20 World Cups?",options: ["India", "England", "Australia", "West Indies"],answer: "West Indies"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first captain to win the IPL?",options: ["MS Dhoni", "Shane Warne", "Gautam Gambhir", "Rohit Sharma"],answer: "Shane Warne"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the name of the cricket stadium in Cape Town, South Africa?",options: ["Wanderers", "Newlands", "SuperSport Park", "Kingsmead"],answer: "Newlands"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is the fastest batsman to reach 8,000 runs in Test cricket?",options: ["Virat Kohli", "Joe Root", "Steve Smith", "Kane Williamson"],answer: "Steve Smith"
    },
    {
        question: "Which cricketer has the highest individual score in T20 internationals?",options: ["Rohit Sharma", "Aaron Finch", "Chris Gayle", "Glenn Maxwell"],answer: "Aaron Finch"
    },
    {
        question: "Who was the first female cricketer to score a double century in ODIs?",options: ["Harmanpreet Kaur", "Smriti Mandhana", "Mithali Raj", "Belinda Clark"],answer: "Belinda Clark"
    },
    {
        question: "Who bowled the fastest ball in cricket history?",options: ["Shoaib Akhtar", "Brett Lee", "Jeff Thomson", "Dale Steyn"],answer: "Shoaib Akhtar"
    },
    {
        question: "Who is the youngest player to score a century in international cricket?",options: ["Shahid Afridi", "Prithvi Shaw", "Rishabh Pant", "Virat Kohli"],answer: "Shahid Afridi"
    }
];


// function for select  5 unique question 
function RandomQuestion() {

    // 1st method  of order log(n)

    // const data = new Set(); /* here we  create data as a set so it comtain 5 different object  if a question repeate then it                          it    not accept it      */
    // while (data.size != 5)  /* we need 5 question so our lop is executes in  5 time  */ {
    //     const index = Math.floor(Math.random() * 50); /* this will generate random value form 0-49 because we have 50 question  in question bank */
    //     data.add(Question_Bank[index]);      /* here we add the selected obj/questin  into data set  */
    // }
    // // return daata    since data is in form of set so we have to convert it into array 
    // return [...data]


    // 2nd nethod of order nlog(n)
    // Question_Bank.sort(()=>Math.random()-0.5);
    // return Question_Bank.slice(0,5);

    // 3rd method 
    const arr=[];
    let length=Question_Bank.length;

    for(let i=0;i<5;i++)
    {
        let index= Math.floor(Math.random()*length);
        arr.push(Question_Bank[index])

        // swap arr[index] with arr[lenght-1]
        [Question_Bank[index],Question_Bank[length-1]]=[Question_Bank[length-1],Question_Bank[index]]
        length--;
    }
    
    return arr;



}

const form = document.getElementById("Quiz-question");
const problem = RandomQuestion(); /* functio  will asign five random obj/question to problem in form of array   */

const original_answer={};


// this random five object/question is present in the problem 
// const problrm = [
//       {
//           question: "Who is known as the 'God of Cricket'?",
//           options: ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Virat Kohli", "MS Dhoni", "Ricky Ponting"],             
//           answer: "Sachin Tendulkar"
//       },
//       {
//           question: "Which country won the first-ever Cricket World Cup in 1975?",
//        options: ["Australia", "England", "West Indies", "India"],
//        answer: "West Indies"
//       },
//       {
//           question: "Who has scored the most international centuries in cricket?",
//        options: ["Virat Kohli", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Ricky Ponting", "Jacques Kallis"],
//        answer: "Sachin Tendulkar"
//       },
//       {
//           question: "What is the highest individual score in ODI cricket?",
//        options: ["264", "237", "219", "200"],
//        answer: "264"
//       },
//       {
//           question: "Who was the first bowler to take 600 Test wickets?",
//        options: ["Shane Warne", "Muttiah Muralitharan", "Anil Kumble", "James Anderson"],
//        answer: "Muttiah Muralitharan"
//       },
      
// ]


// we have to create  5 div 


/* <div>
    <p>
        <label>
            <input></input>
            createTextNode 
        </label>
    </p>
</div> */
problem.forEach((obj, index) => {    /* yha ek ek kar ke 5 object/question  ayega   */

    // creatong array of correct answer of randomely selected 
  original_answer[`q${index+1}`]=obj['answer'];
    /* 
    it contain  the answer in form of 
    {
        q1:
        q2:
    }
    */ 


    // creating div 
    const div_element = document.createElement('div');  /* create a div*/
    div_element.className="Question";


    // creating a paragrtam for question 
    const para = document.createElement('p');
    // para.innerText=obj.question;
    para.innerText = `${index + 1}.${obj.question}`;   /* heer use use index  (index+1 since index start from 0 amnd we need from 1) for question number like 1.  2. 3. */
    div_element.appendChild(para);


    // create    4 option (4label + 4 input) of  the question  
    // options: ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Virat Kohli", "MS Dhoni", "Ricky Ponting"],

        obj.options.forEach((option_value,) => {
        const label = document.createElement('label');
        const input = document.createElement('input');
        input.type="radio";
        input.name = `q${index+1}`;
        input.value = option_value;

        label.appendChild(input);
        label.appendChild(document.createTextNode(option_value));
        div_element.appendChild(label);   /* it is for the option thet we can see in page  */
        div_element.appendChild(document.createElement('br'));
    })

form.appendChild(div_element)
})

// submit and rerty buttton 
const s_button=document.createElement("button");
s_button.id="submit";
s_button.textContent="Submit";
form.appendChild(s_button);




// now Check the answer 
form.addEventListener("submit",(event)=>{
    event.preventDefault();
    const data=new FormData(form);
    let result=0;
    for(let [key,value] of data.entries())
    {
        if(value==original_answer[key])
        result++;
    }
 const output=document.getElementById("output");
 output.innerText=`${result} out of 5`;
})


const R_button=document.createElement("button");
R_button.id="rerty";
R_button.type="reset";
R_button.textContent="Retry";
form.appendChild(R_button);
R_button.addEventListener("click", () => {
    location.reload();  // Reloads the page to generate new questions
});


